<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-28T08:40:23+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Ismail Mechbal</title><subtitle>This is the website of Ismail Mechbal, a Product Engineer based in Stockholm</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Knowledge speaks, but wisdom listens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/knowledge-speaks-but-wisdom-listens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Knowledge speaks, but wisdom listens" /><published>2017-11-28T06:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-28T06:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/knowledge-speaks-but-wisdom-listens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/knowledge-speaks-but-wisdom-listens.html">&lt;p&gt;Knowledge speaks, but wisdom listens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;― Jimi Hendrix&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Knowledge speaks, but wisdom listens.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life in a modern world</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life-in-a-modern-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life in a modern world" /><published>2017-11-27T19:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T19:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life-in-a-modern-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life-in-a-modern-world.html">&lt;p&gt;Life in the modern world is illustrated with Swiping, Scrolling &amp;amp; Touching.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Life in the modern world is illustrated with Swiping, Scrolling &amp;amp; Touching.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When you stop caring about being right in the eyes of everyone . . . it’s amazing how little you care to waste energy trying to convince people of your view.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stop-caring-about-others-peter-attia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When you stop caring about being right in the eyes of everyone . . . it’s amazing how little you care to waste energy trying to convince people of your view." /><published>2017-11-27T11:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T11:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stop-caring-about-others-peter-attia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stop-caring-about-others-peter-attia.html">&lt;p&gt;When you stop caring about being right in the eyes of everyone . . . it’s amazing how little you care to waste energy trying to convince people of your view.
― Peter Attia&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When you stop caring about being right in the eyes of everyone . . . it’s amazing how little you care to waste energy trying to convince people of your view. ― Peter Attia</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Book of Five Rings by Musashi Miyamoto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-book-of-five-rings-musashi-miyamoto.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Book of Five Rings by Musashi Miyamoto" /><published>2017-11-27T10:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T10:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-book-of-five-rings-musashi-miyamoto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-book-of-five-rings-musashi-miyamoto.html">&lt;p&gt;Strategy is the craft of the warrior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immature strategy is the cause of grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know the smallest things and the biggest things, the shallowest things and the deepest things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strategist makes small things into big things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle of strategy is having one thing, to know ten thousand things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, it is difficult for large numbers of men to change position, so their movements can be easily predicted. An individual can easily change his mind, so his movements are difficult to predict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to know yourself if you do not know others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will seem difficult at first, but everything is difficult at first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From one thing, know ten thousand things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should not copy others, but use weapons which you can handle properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is bad for commanders and troopers to have likes and dislikes. These are things you must learn thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not think dishonestly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Way is in training.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Become acquainted with every art.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know the Ways of all professions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distinguish between gain and loss in worldly matters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop intuitive judgement and understanding for everything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perceive those things which cannot be seen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay attention even to trifles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do nothing which is of no use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II - Book of water&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategy is different from other things in that if you mistake the Way even a little you will become bewildered and fall into bad ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In strategy your spiritual bearing must not be any different from normal. Both in fighting and in everyday life you should be determined though calm. Meet the situation without tenseness yet not recklessly, your spirit settled yet unbiased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all forms of strategy, it is necessary to maintain the combat stance in everyday life and to make your everyday stance your combat stance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In strategy it is important to see distant things as if they were close and to take a distanced view of close things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing the Way of the long sword means we can wield with two fingers the sword we usually carry. If we know the path of the sword well, we can wield it easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must train constantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contests of strategy it is bad to be led about by the enemy. You must always be able to lead the enemy about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large-scale strategy, when the enemy starts to collapse, you must pursue him without letting the chance go. If you fail to take advantage of your enemies’ collapse, they may recover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In single combat, the enemy sometimes loses timing and collapses. If you let this opportunity pass, he may recover and not be so negligent thereafter. Fix your eye on the enemy’s collapse, and chase him, attacking so that you do not let him recover. You must do this. The chasing attack is with a strong spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To become the enemy” means to think yourself in the enemy’s position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large-scale strategy, when there is a “four hands” spirit, do not give up - it is man’s existence. Immediately throw away this spirit and win with a technique the enemy does not expect.
In single combat also, when we think we have fallen into the “four hands” situation, we must defeat the enemy by changing our mind and applying a suitable technique according to his condition. You must be able to judge this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large-scale strategy, when the enemy is agitated and shows an inclination to rush, do not mind in the least. Make a show of complete calmness, and the enemy will be taken by this and will become relaxed. When you see that this spirit has been passed on, you can bring about the enemy’s defeat by attacking strongly with a Void spirit.
In single combat, you can win by relaxing your body and spirit and then, catching on to the moment the enemy relaxes, attack strongly and quickly, forestalling him. What is know as “getting someone drunk” is similar to this. You can also infect the enemy with a bored, careless, or weak spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large-scale strategy it is important to cause loss of balance. Attack without warning where the enemy is not expecting it, and while his spirit is undecided follow up your advantage and, having the lead, defeat him.
Or, in single combat, start by making a show of being slow, then suddenly attack strongly. Without allowing him space for breath to recover form the fluctuation of spirit, you must grasp the opportunity to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In single combat, also, you must use the advantage of taking the enemy unawares by frightening him with your body, long sword, or voice, to defeat him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever we have become preoccupied with small detail, we must suddenly change into a large spirit, interchanging large with small.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Strategy is the craft of the warrior.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to say No</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-to-say-no.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to say No" /><published>2017-11-27T10:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T10:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-to-say-no</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-to-say-no.html">&lt;p&gt;Inspiration from the new book of Tim Ferris “Tribe of Mentors” on how to write an email saying No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://tim.blog/2017/11/25/how-to-say-no/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi xxx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope my email reaches you and your beloved one well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful for the invitation to participate in the { position/task }, but I’m struggling at this moment to make time ends meet for my current work as well as my ongoing procrastination with my own projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought carefully about this as it’s clearly a wonderful opportunity, but I’m going to decline –with gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope{ XXX } will be a big success!
Thanks again&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Inspiration from the new book of Tim Ferris “Tribe of Mentors” on how to write an email saying No.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Discipline equals Freedom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/discipline-equals-freedom.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discipline equals Freedom" /><published>2017-11-27T09:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T09:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/discipline-equals-freedom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/discipline-equals-freedom.html">&lt;p&gt;Discipline equals freedom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;― Jocko Willink&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Discipline equals freedom</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The best things in life are free. The second best things are very, very expensive.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-best-things-in-life-are-free-the-second-best-things-are-very-very-expensive.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The best things in life are free. The second best things are very, very expensive." /><published>2017-11-27T08:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T08:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-best-things-in-life-are-free-the-second-best-things-are-very-very-expensive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-best-things-in-life-are-free-the-second-best-things-are-very-very-expensive.html">&lt;p&gt;The best things in life are free. The second best things are very, very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;― Coco Chanel&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The best things in life are free. The second best things are very, very expensive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Live notification when Bostadsnabben is available</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/live-notification-when-bostadsnabben-is-available.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Live notification when Bostadsnabben is available" /><published>2017-11-11T07:57:48+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-11T07:57:48+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/live-notification-when-bostadsnabben-is-available</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/live-notification-when-bostadsnabben-is-available.html">&lt;p&gt;Sweden housing crisis is becoming an international discussion, BBC wrote an interesting article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20160517-this-is-one-city-where-youll-never-find-a-home&quot;&gt;The city with 20-year waiting lists for rental homes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, you’ll need to sign up your child to this list as soon as he is born to ensure he can get a flat when he reaches his 20’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelocal.se/20170828/the-story-of-swedens-housing-crisis&quot;&gt;The local&lt;/a&gt;, wrote an interesting article with some scary numbers: “For an idea of just how long those queues can be, in the Swedish capital, the number of people waiting to rent an apartment from Stockholm’s Housing Agency (Bostadsförmedlingen) grew by almost 40,000 last year – and there are now almost 580,000 waiting to find an apartment through that method (although not everyone in the queue is necessarily actively apartment-hunting).
During the same year only 6,900 new apartment rentals were brokered by the agency. At that pace, it would take half a century for all of the people on the waiting list to earn a standard long-term contract.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a fast track, Bostadsnabben, where the principle is based on first in first out or in other words if you’re the first to apply then the flat is yours, if requirements are met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to see if there is any way to automate this task, at least the first part, getting a notification when a new fast track flat is available, thankfully there is a public endpoint that can serve us.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bostad.stockholm.se/Lista/AllaAnnonser&quot;&gt;https://bostad.stockholm.se/Lista/AllaAnnonser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a small Ruby script that request this endpoint every 5 minutes, 5 times a day from Monday to Friday between 7am and 6pm. The script search for the value of Bostadssnabben: True and if found will post to my Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ismailmechbal/bostadssnabben&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ismailmechbal/bostadssnabben&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been 3 weeks now since the script is deployed and no fast track has been submitted yet!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sweden housing crisis is becoming an international discussion, BBC wrote an interesting article The city with 20-year waiting lists for rental homes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A/B Testing tools of 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ab-testing-tools-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A/B Testing tools of 2018" /><published>2017-09-15T23:57:48+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-15T23:57:48+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ab-testing-tools-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ab-testing-tools-2018.html">&lt;p&gt;A/B Testing is a useful tool that can improve the numbers &amp;amp; adoption of a product. It can be used to boost the landing page conversion rate and more importantly to improve the overall User Experience of the product by adding/removing features or simplifying the design.
Jason Fried’s known for A/B Testing of Basecamp advises “to test radically different things. We don’t know what works. Destroy all assumptions. We need to find what works and keep iterating—keep learning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several &lt;a href=&quot;https://conversion-rate-experts.com/split-testing-software/&quot;&gt;A/B Testing tools&lt;/a&gt; exists in the market, I believe the following two tools will distinguish themself in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/analytics/optimize&quot;&gt;Google Optimize&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-optimize&quot;&gt;Google Optimize&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Optimize as described by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/seanmcquaide&quot;&gt;Sean McQuaide&lt;/a&gt; is “an A/B testing and personalization tool that uses Google Analytics data to power your CRO efforts. Obviously A/B testing is nothing new, neither is serving personalized content based on customer behavior. The true progress here is how Google Optimize pairs with Google Analytics, and how easily we can tie our experiments to KPIs in Google Analytics.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://online-behavior.com/testing/google-optimize&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;google-optimize-advantages&quot;&gt;Google Optimize advantages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to setup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Similar UI to other Google products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advanced targeting &amp;amp; reporting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data synchronization between Google Optimize &amp;amp; Google Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;google-optimize-drawbacks&quot;&gt;Google Optimize drawbacks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Analytics audience targeting not available&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limited Multivariate testing (MVT)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Limited Concurrent Experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However Google offers a premium feature, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/analytics/optimize/compare/&quot;&gt;Google Optimize 360&lt;/a&gt;,  if you need those features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tutorials&quot;&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/360suite/optimize/answer/7012154&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://conversionxl.com/blog/google-optimize/&quot;&gt;Conversionxl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;netlify&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re running your Landing page on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.staticgen.com/&quot;&gt;static site generator framework&lt;/a&gt;, if not then you might &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/blog/2016/05/18/9-reasons-your-site-should-be-static/&quot;&gt;consider it&lt;/a&gt;, chances you’ve heard of Netlify, a tool that “has everything you need to make a high performance site or web-app. You just push your code” Tom Preston-Werner, Founder of GitHub &amp;amp; Creator of Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;netlify-advantages&quot;&gt;Netlify Advantages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy to setup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Branch split testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Track split testing information with Google Analytics or Segment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;netlify-disadvantages&quot;&gt;Netlify Disadvantages&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need a static site generator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only for the techies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No reporting or targeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tutorials-1&quot;&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netlify.com/docs/split-testing/&quot;&gt;https://www.netlify.com/docs/split-testing/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-practices&quot;&gt;Best practices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test What Matters the Most, The Lean Analytics book introduce a notion of the “One Metrics That Matters” (OMTM) implement this approach to get focus on your A/B Test&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test Over Time, Allocating a reasonable time is beneficial as it will provide better insights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/psychd-funnel-conversion&quot;&gt;Psych’d&lt;/a&gt;, A user psychology framework for increasing funnel conversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A/B Testing is a useful tool that can improve the numbers &amp;amp; adoption of a product. It can be used to boost the landing page conversion rate and more importantly to improve the overall User Experience of the product by adding/removing features or simplifying the design. Jason Fried’s known for A/B Testing of Basecamp advises “to test radically different things. We don’t know what works. Destroy all assumptions. We need to find what works and keep iterating—keep learning.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The day I won the elections!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-day-i-won-the-elections.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The day I won the elections!" /><published>2017-09-15T23:57:48+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-15T23:57:48+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-day-i-won-the-elections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-day-i-won-the-elections.html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote this article a while ago in my blog arena. I think it’ll be great to repost it here.
Please enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day I won the elections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear fellow citizen,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll make you sure you’re well entertained watching your idols show while netflix chilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll promise you a longer working hours in a more shittier jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll realize your dream and lets you work long enough until your grandgrand kid becomes your manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll fight to make your retirement pension vanish the day you go collect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When that day comes, I’ll laugh the shit out of you and everyone who elected me as Mr president.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I wrote this article a while ago in my blog arena. I think it’ll be great to repost it here. Please enjoy!</summary></entry></feed>